<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on emosher.dev</title><link>https://emosher.dev/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on emosher.dev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 11:05:33 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://emosher.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ckad</title><link>https://emosher.dev/posts/ckad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 11:05:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://emosher.dev/posts/ckad/</guid><description>How I Got CKAD CKAD is Certified Kubernetes Application Developer, which is a cerfication from the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF). I got mine in March of this year, and I had a couple folks ask about my experience so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d put together some thoughts about it. When I started work on CKAD, I was brand new to Kubernetes. If you&amp;rsquo;ve got experience with Kubernetes then you already have a head start!</description></item><item><title>Blog 2.0</title><link>https://emosher.dev/posts/blog-2-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://emosher.dev/posts/blog-2-0/</guid><description>Well here it is! After months of tinkering (and by tinkering, I mean procrastinating) I have finally moved my blog to Hexo! In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll cover some of the differences between my old and new blog as well as some of the reasons why I decided to migrate.
Prior Set Up Previously, I was running a blog on Ghost using Digital Ocean. And honestly this boiled down to one important thing - the Digital Ocean server was not free.</description></item><item><title>Govern Node Right</title><link>https://emosher.dev/posts/govern-node-right/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 21:37:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://emosher.dev/posts/govern-node-right/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a minute to comment on the Node.js fork known as io.js.
tl;dr - Node.js and io.js should merge and the Node Foundation should use the open governance model proven by io.js
The Fork When io.js started I was mostly apathetic about the fork. I thought it could lead to good things but it was too soon to tell. To quote Eran Hammer&amp;rsquo;s post on the subject: &amp;ldquo;Can things get better?</description></item><item><title>Local Storage to Production</title><link>https://emosher.dev/posts/local-storage-to-production/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 23:29:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://emosher.dev/posts/local-storage-to-production/</guid><description>Some of the javascript projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on never left the prototype phase, but others have made it into some form of production. Every once in a while, I encounter something that causes major ripple effects within my frontend code.
What I encountered recently was the difference between synchronous and asynchronous. While the difference is often obvious, it can be easy to overlook.
LocalStorage is Synchronous! Enter localStorage. I sometimes see apps that are in the prototype phase using local storage as a way to store data.</description></item><item><title>Ghost 0.5</title><link>https://emosher.dev/posts/ghost-0-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 18:53:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://emosher.dev/posts/ghost-0-5/</guid><description>A week ago Ghost 0.5 was released and this blog is now upgraded to 0.5.
Thanks to the Ghost documentation and How to Install Ghost, the upgrade process was a breeze.
Features See the Ghost blog for the full list of features.
Ghost 0.5 brings a whole host of new features. A newly refactored admin interface, public JSON API, and multiple user support.
New Release Schedule These new features are great, but what I am most excited about is the new release schedule.</description></item><item><title>Building Smarter Directives #2</title><link>https://emosher.dev/posts/building-smarter-directives-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 22:29:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://emosher.dev/posts/building-smarter-directives-2/</guid><description>My last post talked about conditionally loading templates using ng-include.
I spent a good amount of time using this, but found it to be problematic because it was causing my HTML to become bloated. Instead of adding to the div soup, I set out to find a better way.
This leads to nested divs:
&amp;lt;div ng-include=&amp;#34;contentUrl&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; Renders something like this:
&amp;lt;div ng-include=&amp;#34;contentUrl&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; This is the template &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; As it turned out, there are options!</description></item><item><title>Building Smarter Directives</title><link>https://emosher.dev/posts/building-smarter-directives/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 22:30:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://emosher.dev/posts/building-smarter-directives/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working a lot with AngularJS directives recently.
If you are not familiar with AngularJS or directives, head over to the AngularJS tutorial and developer guide to get up to speed.
Template vs. TemplateUrl If you are like me, you like to keep HTML out of your JavaScript. When I&amp;rsquo;m writing my directives, I almost always keep templates in seperate HTML files rather than using inline templates (see below for an example).</description></item><item><title>AngularJS App Walkthrough</title><link>https://emosher.dev/posts/angularjs-app-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 23:32:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://emosher.dev/posts/angularjs-app-walkthrough/</guid><description>While preparing to give a talk, I built a simple step by step application with AngularJS. The steps are there to show some of the features of Angular, and how an application might progress through development.
When I was learning Angular (around 1.0), what I found to be the most lacking was practical examples. I hope it helps those that are learning the &amp;ldquo;Angular way.&amp;rdquo;
Jawa The application renders information about open source projects, links to the project Github page, and renders the project&amp;rsquo;s Readme document in the browser.</description></item><item><title>3 Months of Code?</title><link>https://emosher.dev/posts/3-months-of-code/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 23:52:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://emosher.dev/posts/3-months-of-code/</guid><description>I stumbled upon Hacker School today. It really sounds like a neat idea, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure that it has helped some of the people that had the chance to go there.
But it got me thinking &amp;hellip; what if I had 3 months to work on whatever code I wanted to?
What am I truly passionate about? If I had 3 months to code anything I wanted what would that be?</description></item><item><title>Computer Science vs. Software Engineering</title><link>https://emosher.dev/posts/computer-science-vs-software-engineering/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 21:37:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://emosher.dev/posts/computer-science-vs-software-engineering/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Computer Science&amp;rdquo; vs. &amp;ldquo;Software Engineering&amp;rdquo;
That dichotomy is something that I have seen for as long as I have been involved with technology. I see lots of brilliant people that can talk theories, concepts, and patterns all day long. When it comes to building useful working applications, that is not their strong suit.
Before we go further&amp;hellip; As much as the preceeding statements may seem inflammatory, that&amp;rsquo;s not the intent. The way I see it - there is merit to both Computer Science and Software Engineering.</description></item><item><title>Welcome!</title><link>https://emosher.dev/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 09:47:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://emosher.dev/posts/welcome/</guid><description>Welcome to my blog. Here you will find the ranting and raving of a Software Engineer, musician, techie, open source fan/advocate and gamer.
First Things First I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting here about any and all things related to technology, music, and world events. While I may mention world events and/or the politics surrounding them, I tend to stay away from purely political discussions. Sure, I have opinions but I&amp;rsquo;ll leave the politicking to the politicians.</description></item></channel></rss>